[Music]
y' think too small I got Big Dreams you
just starting them way ahead at the end
scenes started reading and dodging all
of the quick sches money like your
[Music]
Spotify I'm Dani I'm Sarah and this is
now the dealmakers podcast because most
of you guys can't spell inquisitive I'm
not going to hold it against
you it's a madeup word I mean for
spelling be purp no it is in the
dictionary it is a real word thank you
yes it's Webster defines acquisitive as
our podcast that we created no anyway so
yeah your fault not ours we changed it
to dealmakers it's cooler anyway I like
it on the dealmakers podcast we bring on
dealmakers we're going to interview
dealmakers who have completed
Acquisitions or are M experts so we can
talk about all the things that can go
wrong all the red flags to look out for
and uh teach you how to avoid them today
we have Zack Toyota a entrepreneur
business developer an amazing background
I can't wait to uh to to hear it all
again and to go deeper um but Zach is
the chir and CEO of self-d disrupt and
uh we're glad to have you yeah thank you
very much for having me on how did you
get started what made you decide to get
into Acquisitions I don't have a
traditional education in finance ORS
business or anything like that I went to
Florida State University and got my
degree in criminal justice so I thought
I was going to be a cop and along the
way I just got involved in night life
and and got blessed to learn the
business side of that and I was
extremely intrigued and mainly intrigued
by all the different ways folks are
figuring out how to make money and I'm
so you know dead set on this uh salary
career there's nothing wrong with it but
it has a cap so uh I wouldn't say I'm an
m&a expert but I am an expert in being
really Scrappy and resourceful and being
creative in the ways that I figured it
out so I like to say that I'm I have a
self- baked business education and over
the last decade I've cut my teeth in
call centers disruptive startups and
emerging Industries and um most recently
in private Equity Consulting and um the
where it all started was in my early 20s
I was working with these startups that
were going through Acquisitions or going
through um some sort of deal flow and I
got insights into the integration side
of either bringing in a new business and
how to integrate the technology Andor
just being a fly on the wall for these
conversations on the leadership team
discussing the whole deal and again
fascinating and I was dead set on I want
to do a deal you know I'm really I need
to figure this out I think that's where
my passion is I've been in all these
different sectors and I seem to be able
to figure it out so let's let's do this
myself and obviously I'm young and I
have an opinion and I and I think the
best thing ever at the time when you're
early in your 20s I haven't got beaten
up enough yet um but what I did figure
out was with my free time I could work
at night and I wanted to do something
that people weren't willing to do and I
had that just like beaten in my head
over and over for a month or two until I
discovered cleaning I I should just
start cleaning offices or find a
cleaning businesses that's after hours
and that's what I went and did and it
was super easy anybody can do it I was
able to figure out how to you know own
and oper that business and and it wasn't
again as simple as hey I called around
and found somebody willing to exit it
was I called around all the local
competitive businesses who I'm
essentially their newest competitor and
I said hey I'm I'm this guy I'm new in
town small fish do you have any accounts
you hate or any accounts that you just
want to offload I'd love to take them
off your hands I'll work you in I'll
give you some sort of commission but
keep me in mind you know no harm no foul
you know I just want you to know him
around and there was an
a local business who was actually um
winding down their clean their
commercial cleaning operations and they
gifted me essentially 10 accounts that I
worked on that sucked by the way they're
their 10 worst accounts and I I learned
on the Fly for two years every single
night that's all I did I skipped
holidays my family didn't see me and I
was just dead set on this is I'm going
to grow this business and go roll up a
couple local cleaning businesses and I
didn't achieve the rollup and I I
ultimately ended up becoming very burnt
out and uh I just because I was trying
to do everything but it led me to
discovering search funds and search
funds was this ability to go and find a
sponsor who believes in me who's going
to go pay for me to to go buy a business
together and I was like great idea just
you know find somebody who wants to bet
on Zack Toyota and I learned again very
quickly I had no traditional background
I didn't come from Goldman Sachs or you
know some hedge fund and no sponsor was
willing to bet on me just yet because I
I did a commercial cleaning company
they're like hey man kudos to you you
took out the trash but that's not going
to you know that's not going to convince
us just yet so um I ended up going back
and just figuring out through actually
leveraging
LinkedIn U how to get that experience
and I found this hedge fund emerging
hedge fund in South Florida that was
willing to bring me on on the marketing
side and the investor relations side and
I got a crash course in Deal flow and
deal origination and you name it and
throughout that time I had my ears to
the street and a lot of opportunities
came my way and I discovered micro SAS
Acquisitions that applied all these
search funds principles all these
principles of due diligence and deal
flow through private Equity but I didn't
have to raise a million dollars to do it
so I was instantly sold and I went and
found a deal in the micro SAS space and
that's what I've been up to for the past
year so in a long-winded way that's
that's me the past last decade and where
I've come from I was a glorified janitor
to here I am now running and owning and
operating a portfolio of companies what
what happened to the cleaning company I
exited it to uh somebody very similar to
me who was C excuse me coming into the
market a few of the businesses were
closing down so they no longer needed
the service I full transparency didn't
do an amazing job growing organically
growing new accounts I just managed the
book I was gifted and throughout that
time I ended up offloading that to
somebody El who was coming on and
hanging around for 12 months making sure
they didn't crash the bus basically
acting as a therapist and then you know
once he was had his feet in the ground
he was off and running and I I left him
you know there I'm very interested in
this micras acquisition thing but I
think if I'm our listeners they probably
would like to hear your view of uh the
janitorial commercial cleaning type of
Industry a lot of people I get calls a
lot from people who are you know riding
Lis right now in that industry is it um
you have you know I'm from east
Tennessee and we do a lot of caving
there called like
spelunking um but you've spelunked the
industry you have like found all of the
um bats and weird cave features what
what would you think what would you say
to somebody who was looking to acquire
in that space you have to be really open
to doing the work and effectively build
a mental callous of doing that work and
and just owning that because because a
cleaning business is the ultimate get it
done job if you don't do a good job you
will get a phone call in the morning and
they're not calling to tell you hey the
bathroom looks great you'll never get
that call but you will get a call when
things don't look so good so you just
have to execute and it's simple simple
stupid it's taking out the trash and
doing the small things right but you
just build this uh Cadence or this uh
momentum and I'm a big believer in
inertia but you bu build this momentum
of just doing it every day doing the
hard work where anything else just
doesn't matter I just took out the trash
and cleaned up the toilets what's next
you know it doesn't really get worse
from here I have so much passion for how
you got into that business I that
resonates so much with me um when I went
from bail bonds to accounting I did the
same exact thing my thought was I was a
solo preneur I was a small business
owner my accountant never answered the
phone they didn't want to give me the
time a day so I called accountants when
I was getting into it and said hey do
you have a whole bunch of small
businesses that you know they billables
aren't very high it's not really worth
your time uh let me take them I'll help
them out and uh and then and then then
getting into business brokerage same
thing I tell I tell the brokers in my
office all the time like hey somebody's
somebody's making you pull your hair out
send them my way let me learn on those
it's the beauty of asking the question
sometimes people just get scared or
don't have they have the wear with all I
shouldn't say that but they for some
reason they don't take action on just
asking ask around if it's embarrassing
you for whatever reason Reon you have to
get over that if you want to be a
business owner and an operator there's a
lot of things you're not going to be an
expert at you just got to figure it out
you're basically the best project
manager on the planet until you really
get your arms around the business uh
because you're working with so many
different you know facets of the
business while you're providing value in
your area of expertise but yeah it
starts with you just have to ask that
question do you think there are deals to
be made uh in U you know commercial
cleaning janitorial services like do you
think you can grow those and
roll up and the 100% a lot of them
mainly because the fact that they're not
sexy quote unquote there's not often a
secession plan and sometimes the
businesses aren't big enough for private
Equity to care so there is some sort of
handoff at some point and it's either a
waiting game or you find a motivated
seller who wants a quote unquote mentee
to you know kind of bring along with
them to guide their baby and and through
the next wave or the Next Generation and
there's tons of those out there mainly
because kids these days aren't growing
up saying Hey I want to start a cleaning
business it's just not happening it's
true I think a lot about the Arbitrage
of uh enthusiasm that investment is
because when you're young you have
enthusiasm and no money and when you're
older You've Lost Your Enthusiasm but
you have the money so you invest in a
younger person who has that's why exist
yeah it's enthusiasm
Arbitrage and um I I'm not clear where I
am in that Spectrum but I'm definitely
waning so I hope I have investor money
soon because otherwise it's a mess but
um you know when you do have that
enthusiasm and you are young and Pie in
the Sky that's not your first go-to so
it is you know you're looking at the
kind of sexier less less born business
types so you do have to find that
precipice of somebody who's been around
enough to have realized the potential
and appreciate it but still has all of
that enthusiasm and energy to stay up
all night cleaning and taking out the
trash like you described there's an
aspect especially these days with
everything online that's really
glamorous and instant gratification and
these are the type of businesses that
just don't get that recognition or don't
get that uh
marketability or or or big push you know
to put it in front of there's I could
probably Google this right now there's
probably 50 to 100 commercial cleaning
businesses here in in Fort Lauderdale
Miami date area I don't see any of their
on Instagram there's probably good
reason for that but it's just not coming
across my desk it's probably not coming
across others desk so it's just a matter
of you know go go sniff it out there's
there's businesses out there and my
number one goal is I need to find
something I could do at night that's all
I'll started what can I do at night I
don't want to be a security guard I
don't want to buy a security guard
business what's easy and as I'm doing
this this lady's in my office making a
ton of noise and I'm like oh my God
that's fantastic and then you went
immediately from that that into uh you
know this micro sass which is one of
those things you see when we talk tons
about the um the you know influence or
buy a small business and run it from
your yacht um and usually that doesn't
have anything to do with commercial
cleaning companies but often people are
like pick up some micras companies um so
is it as that are you on a yacht right
now no no I'm sitting in my office doing
doing the same thing I was doing you
know 10 years ago just grinding it out
and and keep my head down I'm it's so
cliche but I'm I'm a big believer in
just staying at bat and Swinging away
you're going to have your strikeouts
your singles you're going to get your
home runs but you just got to stick
around and understand that it's a
everyday process and it's the same thing
with the cleaning business day over day
discipline and that stuff compounds in a
big way and you have to you know make
yourself the hero of your own story
unless you're just one of those people
who glorifies or or puts it out on
Instagram your story that's cool but for
me it's you know as long as I'm here
every day showing up I feel really good
about I'm moving in the right direction
and I will get my big pop and throughout
this entire time I'm getting nothing but
an amazing experience which is you know
you can't teach that you have to go
through it every day that's why I have I
have so much respect for you Zach and
that's why I wanted to have you on
that's why I enjoy all of the
conversations that we have uh because
there's there's no shortage of like
influencers out there especially in Tech
that talk about the wins and you know
really hold themselves out there as
being this Guru this expert and
everything I've ever seen you in you're
like I'm in the trenches I'm still doing
the work and uh and you know I don't
know I I feel like it's your like that's
your personality like to get in there
and build something that hasn't been
built before I particularly enjoy it I
like seeing things evolve in front of me
from idea to you know operating that I
get in crazy amount of satisfaction from
that and doing it over and over in new
Industries I get even more sa like from
early days I'm just naturally so curious
and how everything works and when I see
a bigger goal or a bigger Target I'm
like oh yeah I can't sleep at night I I
want to keep you know running for the
next thing and I my mentor gave me a
book called the next Mountain no the
second Mountain excuse me because he's
like this is your personality in a nsh
show you're just Mountain one two you
just always are going for that you know
your second Mountain so he's like I'm so
curious to see in 50 years where you
land I'm not a fan of your business but
I'm a fan of Zack Toyota so keep it
going all
thanks I appreciate it yeah I mean
that's so much more significant um but
how did you I don't have a ton of
experience in the SAS acquisition space
and I always assumed the deals that the
deals that I have done have been so um
Niche and it's you know people working
already in the industry and it's you
know enterprise software that they have
built for a specific thing and you know
everybody seems to understand it and I
do the legal part but you didn't come
from a SAS background that I'm hearing
how did you even get interested in this
and how did you vet it how would you
ever know what a good deal was my due
diligence process in the beginning could
have been done on the back of a napkin
it was you know I found something online
or somebody provided me their their
their process and but I treated it like
a list and this is you know my advice to
anyone out there and this is a big
learning experience was uh due diligence
is purely about finding red flags it is
not a checklist and I made the mistake
of treating it like a checklist in the
beginning because I didn't know any
better and I didn't have legal around me
to guide me I was you know asking the
wrong questions more than likely and so
I learned fast that it has to be you
know identify red flags sniff that out
then what's your thesis to grow sniff
that out because you don't want to lose
enthusiasm but you have to go right away
into risk assumptions and basically
spend a whole weekend poking holes in in
your new balloon and then from there
it's okay I still feel good about this I
don't want to kill it let's find out
operating leverage and and dive in and
that's it's really quick one two you
know keep it simple stupid I I like to
operate that way because I don't have
that traditional education so I have to
find ways that are effective but I'm not
drowning in spreadsheets that I don't
understand if that makes sense risk
assumption I love that I love that
phrase um we talk about risk assessment
all the time but I see so many people
who are so excited to do a deal so eager
to get into a deal that um you know
they'll they'll explain away make
excuses
Overlook um but but not make those risk
assumptions and uh and get into bad
deals I like started the briefest
startup a million years ago um that was
shoe repair by mail and um lost
enthusiasm almost immediately when I
found a single
competitor just one I mean I was in my
early 20s and I reflect on that and I'm
like there was one competitor it was a
blue ocean of you know and these guys
were completely different um but you
know how do you vet the competition when
you're looking at a SAS product and
you're not steeped in SAS all the time
well for me I built a scorecard I knew
what I wanted and so to quickly
backtrack I didn't Dive Right into SAS I
ended up when I sold off the cleaning
business uh the day the company I was
working for during the day got acquired
so I had a lot of time on my hands all
of a sudden and because I was getting my
teeth kicked in on search funds and you
know I'm on LinkedIn all day long trying
to find mentors and River guides anyone
who could help me and they're like you
you know you don't have the background
you what's your degree in just have you
ever run a business all the normal stuff
they should be asking it's their money
I'm asking for and their time so I just
didn't have good answers so I I was like
you know what I need to find the answers
or I need to find the experience so I
did a crash course at so it was a hedge
fund here in South Florida that was
doing real estate development deals so I
spent two years doing that but I was
leveraging LinkedIn so much that I was
like I'm spending way too much time on
LinkedIn poking around on their profiles
it's effective but my whole job is
turned into like this like LinkedIn guy
in the corner so I went and looked for
tools to help me and to help expedite my
process and I came across a few
companies I really liked and two
FasTrack two years later at a charity
golf event that we threw through that
firm
uh one of the gentlemen came up to me
he's like hey we've known each other
through Linkedin I used to be with this
company I came home and I started my own
thing and I was like love it let's talk
and he basically created a micro SAS
firm he' been operating for a year it
was a young team they needed an they
needed an operating partner pretty badly
and just didn't know it and they also
didn't really know what they were
sitting on I I had a good feeling that
if we combined forces with what I was
just able to achieve on LinkedIn with
them Expediting this process it was just
this aha moment so it fell in my lap I
didn't have to go do a lot of vetting I
just really really knew what I wanted
because I personally was using something
like this every day to help myself buy
back hours or or or take back hours in
my own day so I instantly knew the value
and felt I could sell this thing with a
lot of Integrity because I was
personally using it and I personally
believed in things like this and Daniel
and I know what uh your product is but
can you explain it software platform
called self-d disrupt it's an omni
Channel sales engagement platform so
it's a really fancy way of saying we
help automate your Outreach process on
LinkedIn email text Styler you name it
so effectively you can go and just
manage your pipeline take demos or or
qualify these opportunities while the
software is in the background running
and finding these opportunities are
helping grow your network so that you
can go ahead and populate more
opportunities so you can either leverage
it for the sales side leverage it for
building your network I've seen people
leverage it for U raising Capital
selling their business buying businesses
finding board members and just strictly
deal flow so it really has become you
know an all-in-one tool to help
accelerate startups to help accelerate
agencies and anybody who's a disruptive
founder who wants to carve out their
market share on the internet we can help
them quickly achieve that with this
technology it has been a GameChanger
because and I I wholeheartedly believe
what you said that um you know when
you're selling it's so much easier to
sell something that you one need that
you are using um but then you you know
something that you really truly believe
in yeah and uh man I was I was spending
hours on LinkedIn manually searching
profiles uh looking into people liking
commenting um yeah when I when I
discovered you guys uh you know really
early on I'm I'm super super fortunate
to have like kind of gotten in the early
days um yeah it was a game changer from
day one and I'm excited about all the
new features coming out awesome I love
it you were were really bullish on
LinkedIn early like sounds like like you
were doing this a while ago when when
most people were looking at LinkedIn as
like a resume site yeah
people yeah so what was it about
LinkedIn that that stood out to you as
as this opportunity as this space and
and how'd you get into that early so
funny story I was at a startup
who couldn't find like how to Market and
I pitched the founder like hey we should
just make a LinkedIn and let me kind of
go crazy with it and he's like yeah
whatever you're wasting your time and it
brought in some some good amount uh on
the revenue side nothing to go waving my
flag but I had like this aha moment and
as I was transitioning out of that job
into this new disruptive space which was
Cannabis I found out within the first
month as I'm poking around hey why
aren't we marketing on Facebook why
don't we have an Instagram why don't we
have this they're like oh we get banned
man we get shut down fast so I was like
okay that's interesting and uh so after
you know I got my feet wet there I
invested in my own dollars doing I
called it CBD Toyota and I basically did
like reals before they are reals a
talking head of educating people about
CBD and cannaboids and not selling
anything or ever mentioning weed or
cannabis just education and the page
blew up it was you know growing faster
than the company page they brought me to
meeting and they're like who are you
what are you doing because at the time
they brought anyone in for uh commission
only sales and I cold called my way into
that job by the way I just showed up and
they never asked me to leave so that's
like a whole another story but they're
like hey like what's the CBD Toyota
thing what are you doing and I explained
it to them and they're like oh whoa we
didn't know we could get away with that
I was like hey you guys should try it on
LinkedIn and they're like do it start
the company page take over the founders
pages and uh within a month we found a
high-risk Merchant processor which was
super hard to find at the time in
cannabis we did $50 million through that
company that year so it was a big deal
that we locked that in uh we found
multiple partners including you know
getting into CVS finding partners for
lobbying because we helped write a bill
for the State of Florida for the the
hemp farm bill just a lot of tremendous
massive things to help pave this way for
this industry all coming through
Linkedin so I'm like married to this
thing by now I I believe in it I know we
can do it but it was because of how
effective it was for cannabis principles
and how we were able to just own the
whole cannabis Market in CBD and hemp
for like two years on LinkedIn and I
really mean that we're dominating you
couldn't go on without seeing a post
from one of our Founders or from company
it was
insane I was I was set and now it has a
billion users so it's just a platform of
decision makers or industry experts or
people who are up and coming or a talent
pool it's endless if you can't figure
out how to find one good person to talk
to on LinkedIn you're doing it wrong and
you should hit me up it's a good
endorsement for LinkedIn yeah our new
sponsor Toyota says it the the guy not
the car company don't get I was just
wondering if Toyota the car company has
ever take an issue with your using I
tried to start a uh Toyota Ventures I
submitted it to the State of Florida and
like it takes like 30 days for those
things to get processed I found out in
48 hours you're like shut it down not
happening where do you live prove that's
your real name I was like whoa okay
we're gonna go with a different name
here yeah that's I would imagine it
would go that
way as a lawyer they they sneezed on me
and shut that down really fast so
LinkedIn is now much much more popular
than it was I think a lot of people are
starting to realize that that you can
Target and connect with your the ideal
uh people opportunities that that you
would want um but now that's kind of
there's been like an over adjustment
like I get inundated Every Single Day
sales message after sales message and
there's a a catchphrase that you guys
use in um yeah correct me if I'm wrong
because I'm not sure exactly if it's
just if it's part of the content or if
it's like actually part of your your uh
brand um but you at scale uh I think
that's it's such a cool concept when so
many people are like you know AI
commenting or you know AI messaging or
you know spam spam messaging um how can
people today in you know uh you know may
2024 leverage LinkedIn at scale but
without getting getting screened as just
another you know kind of spam
salesperson I ask myself that a lot
because this is my Niche and product and
sometimes it is frowned upon so I have
to be an advocate and you know
evangelist at at certain times and it's
a bummer because it really is an
effective tool if you're not spamming
people so I would say right off the bat
don't pitch slap people if you just send
someone this you know a link to your
countly first message they don't even
know you that's weird so at self-d
distru with sets us apart is we've spent
so much time on LinkedIn me coming from
the side of managing Founders profiles
so it's like all about their voice and
reputation in tone and then my partner
who created a technology to accelerate
all this Outreach so combining the two
we're just so particular about
protecting the client's profile that we
we literally onboard them you can't just
sign up and use the tool you have to go
through an onboarding we help you set up
your campaigns we help you set up the
Cadence we give you the best practices
and we really really recommend you stick
to it because one you're going to see
results but it's also we don't want our
name associated with somebody just
blasting everybody and their mother out
there so it's a it's kind of a white
glove handholding process that we've
been able to create Assets in a video
course and and all these things to
surround that so it's a little less
labor intensive on our end but the
principles are still true we really want
to make sure that you understand what
you're doing and how to be a human using
this tool not to send somebody five
messages five minutes apart I'm so
interested in this let me understand
your role into the acquisition of this
micro SAS company product like are you
currently an owner of the company are
you a co-owner or 100% owner yeah Co
co-owner my so the company I acquired I
I brought the founder on as a partner
okay he did so I like to at least in
this stage of what I'm looking to
acquire like product Le founders
technical Founders who really really
understand what they've built they just
might have struggled on the sales and
marketing side or just hit a wall and
don't know how to get it past that wall
and that's I found somebody who was
amazing at the marketing side amazing at
the sales side he was just
operationally didn't have the experience
he's a very young guy so it was I was
able to come in with hey man I just had
to do x amount of deals for this real
estate firm that I
have limited experience doing but we
were able to achieve all these huge prod
you know project at scale I believe if
we just combine those same practices and
and uh operational systems here we're
going to go really far and let me just
get you out of your own way you know in
the nicest way possible and he was all
for it he he saw where the bottleneck
was and we had stayed in touch
throughout quite some time because I had
originally reached out to him looking
for a tool like this so he knew I was
familiar and you know I just I believed
in him I believed in the product he
built it was just a matter matter of I
needed to put the resources around him
for him to be as successful as possible
and that's essentially what we embarked
on doing and it's been about 16 months
now company's profitable doing an
amazing job seeing consistent
month-over-month growth and really no
major blowup so taking something
rebranding it and stabilizing it is
something I'm really really proud of
because I don't I don't again come from
a shop that does this I kind of read a
book it was like I think this is doable
can we shout him out yeah his name's
Daniel wax he's amazing you you could
probably see him just as much as you see
me on LinkedIn if you're watching this
Danny thanks so much for connecting us
uh together Danny is the one that
introduced to me to Zach so that's how
we that's how we got connected isn't
that as LinkedIn like people connector
or connecting good people to good people
see The Branding is working that's in my
mind he is a sales machine Zach I have
no doubt that you're that you're an OG
business developer and salesman but but
if you comment on something from Danny
wax or you s him a message he's calling
your phone in five minutes oh no he's
A's he's an animal and he does it he's
just a pro that's what's so cool about
him being so young is he's like
naturally figured it out and with some
great guidance and you know so something
that I did that's really unique to a
startup is I put together a board we're
not a huge company we're not doing
billions of dollars but I I did want
governance so I put together a board of
people who have been there and done that
on the tech side on the acquisition side
on all the above so we I structured it
for not only for myself but for my
partner Danny so that we have crash
dummies around us who can say like hey I
don't you know I don't know if I would
do that here's why so two young guys who
you know might be thickheaded at times
when you're bullish on something it's
hard to
see The Next Step as you know being
problematic so that's I intentionally
did that because both of us are young up
and coming upand cominging leaders but I
am very aware that I don't know
everything how often is the board
involved in your decisions and how often
do you meet and stuff that seems like a
really appeal to a lot of my clients at
least once a month I I speak to some of
them more frequently than others just
based on their area of expertise or the
need at that time and then there's
others that are just more of Hey listen
like you have my Rolodex or I'm a
resource and then we have some original
investors who are more in the as silent
Partners um but they are experts in
their own right where where they come in
is when we're ready to exit this
business is they're going to go ahead
and step into
the role of let's position the company
for the exit and get that road show
going so whether it's coming from my
network or theirs they're going to be
assisting in that process apologies in
advance for what my mom tells me I asked
two directive questions since I went to
law school but do you pay those advisors
with no okay no I I because I had a
create come come in in a really creative
way again this wasn't an outright I buy
Danny's business we figured out you know
a really creative way to partner
together and the way that I posed it to
him and he agreed was like look we need
people who have done this around us I
don't have we don't have the bankroll to
fund it uh we don't have the cash flow
to fund it let's carve out um a small
Equity piece and then bring in experts
and offer them Equity based on
Milestones or level of participation and
that's what we did so we kind of
incentivized people with equity in the
business I see so you've got this you
know that's a that's an issue that a lot
of uh
startup Founders and deal makers face
where they are I get I get told this
every day right I have somebody who's
really smart in the business I'm nervous
about going out on my own I'm going to
give them 10% Equity starting out so
they'll have some skin in the game and
they never hear from the person again
right um so I'm always trying to
safeguard that but by associating you
know the equity grants with milestones
and levels of
participation that's a good way to solve
for that issue yeah and in a unique
position I was in is two of the found
the two of the folks on my board I just
went through an acquisition at that
cannabis company so we had a ton of
experience going through a Rebrand and
then so I was like felt comfortable
bringing them on and they're obviously
amazing in what they do because we just
had a huge tremendous success together
as a team so and the other founder was
somebody who was monitoring that and
actually was somebody I met throughout
that acquisition process for the
Cannabis company who just took a liking
to me so he wanted to stay in touch it
evolved to him becoming a Founder on our
or partner on our board excuse me and
then Danny brought some some really
great people to the table from his
previous business and one of them ended
up sticking around and and becoming a
board member for our company as well so
it was all through proximity we did do a
vetting process but I didn't go out and
like blast randoms I just had a kind of
built a bench of people that I trusted
and had worked with and although I
continue to build that bench I likely
will continue to work with people that I
have executed with in the past because
it's we proven it I know uh Sarah you
and I have talked about the Consulting
for Equity before I mentioned I've got
two deals now where I'm going to be
taking a minority Equity position to
consult um I think it's a really cool
thing to put together a personal board
of directors I do think it has to be
done very
carefully um but but man can it really
accelerate you um so Zach I know you
mentioned working with people you had
done deals with in the past people that
you know well uh you know if you were
just to put it out there you know if
someone's hearing this and they're
thinking you know I'm really lonely I'm
trying to do this alone I don't know I
don't know what I don't know um and they
want to go and seek out some some uh
their personal
board uh what should they look for
whether it's in their personal Network
or on LinkedIn where I would start is
you have to quickly identify what you're
an expert in or where you're strong in
and then immediately start plugging the
holes of listen if you're not good with
accounting find somebody who is even if
it's shortterm or pay pay somebody if
you're not going to bring in you know
that quote unquote that board member but
that's the beauty of LinkedIn is you can
go and you can find a lot of retired
folks who have been through Acquisitions
or exited companies who have that
experience that are one more than likely
willing to at least take a phone call
and answer some questions and if you
build a relationship or stay in touch
that person is now a candidate for
whatever you're embarking on because
they proven it you guys now have a
personal relationship they're taking
your calls that's a big deal so that's
where I would start is look around
friends and family but go find somebody
who's been there done that in the area
that you suck at which is hard to admit
sometimes every solar preneur wants to
be the man I have been there but if if
you want to go far find I call him a
river god you just got to find somebody
who knows where that problem is coming
up and can say hey here's my advice take
it or leave it or they'll let you fall
on your face and then they'll remind you
like hey this is my advice and then you
start to respect their opinion a little
bit more but that's the whole point of
bringing on the board is you don't have
to like what they say but you should
very very you know you should be mindful
to it because they've seen this thing a
million times and you're you know young
grasshopper essentially I mean I can
definitely endorse that advice and if
anybody's listening to this and and
feels any kind of doubt trust me just
try it go try it I don't know I'm not
gonna try to I'm not gonna try to sell
you on it I'm thinking of all the people
who pick pick my brain and I'm so happy
to talk about a buying and selling
accounting practices cuz that's my jam
and um I'm like Sarah sharp with no idea
how to do deals and I didn't give her
retainer I just uh had a discovery call
and now she's my podcast I do it all the
time so maybe will eventually come of it
absolutely startup CEOs uh Venture
capitalists investors I I have calls
with people all the time just because I
just hit them up I I message them like a
human I ask for help and they they reach
back out influencers don't even be
afraid if somebody's got a 100 thousand
plus followers like they're they're
inundated with these like you know BS
pitch slaps and Robo messages all day
long and hit them up like a person I bet
you they respond that's this is now the
first time I've heard pitch slap and I
love it so much Zach when you said it
earlier I was like I've got to write
that down yeah do we need to bleep that
out might as well so people like what
did you say yeah that's exactly what it
is it just feels like you know you get
this message that's five paragraphs and
and they spell your name wrong and they
ask what you do and you're like dude did
you even look at my profile it drives me
nuts so you know it's a bot or you see
things misspelled and you're like hey
man whoever's running your technology
sucks you should you should let us take
a stab at it well you've got the same
type of you've got the H issue that my
name has too where you're like don't put
an H on sack don't put an H on Sarah
could be anything literally right
there it's in my email address we've
covered so much ground from from
building a business selling a business
uh putting putting deals together um
Matt micro SAS I think we could we could
probably have a whole episode on on just
how to find SAS acquisition me
everybody's talking about boring
businesses boring businesses have become
popular now now we have to go back the
other way and do the do the unpopular
thing and buy SAS companies but Zach so
I mean I'm I'm a big fan of self-d
disrupt I um you know I love it it's
it's probably sending people messages
and connection requests for me right
this very second um so big fan what's I
know and I know how it is in SAS like I
know everything is kind of like stealth
until it happens gets big announcements
but but what's come what comes next are
you looking to buy more uh different
companies you bolting on more like
what's what's next in the World of
Acquisitions for Zack Toyota it's a bit
of a mix of buy and build and just
straight up build and scale now that
we've had a success um some of our board
has been keen on hey you know let's
potentially go on a spending spree and
buy the next thing and then we have done
a really good job building up cash
reserves or we could potentially go and
and pay for building the next thing
internally which would be amazing uh
because again it's just keep keeping
more I IP
inhouse
and the way that
I the way that I view the next thing is
I want to build the tools that Founders
and startups are going to need in 2030
my business partner is in the same boat
so we're trying to find tools in the
automation sales enablement marketing
enablement anything with AI that that
effectively helps accelerate the sales
process we really truly believe in that
that business development and growth
tools are going to be the next wave
startups are no longer going to take
bets on paying somebody 40 Grand a year
to try to figure it out they're going to
spend 1,500 bucks a month to have a
badass Tech stack that figures it out
for them and now they just need to find
a somebody who's really good at doing
the demo or taking the the original
sales call or they can do it themselves
because it's saves them so much time
those are the things that I personally
use so when I find something I use every
day and I'm like man this is really
interesting and I use it more than a
month then I start thinking how how can
I do this how can I build this thing on
my own or or I reach out to the founders
and I get to know them and I asked
sometimes like hey what's your what's
your plan here you want to exit keep me
in mind and you know again just being
candid and Brash about asking questions
but in a professional way you know
acting acting as if you know we're all
grow here and it's not predatory or like
I'm not a shark but I am trying to scale
my portfolio and make a lot of money and
have fun while I'm doing it so I'm very
clear on that if people are interested
in self- disrupt or they want you on
their personal board of directors uh
where where can they find you where can
they find self-d disrupt how can they
how can they give you money find me on
LinkedIn Zack Toyota it's not hard to to
mess that one up unless you spelled the
Zack with an H but we covered that
earlier so hopefully they get that one
yeah mitigated that right away and if
not you could find us on LinkedIn that's
that's our bread and butter our whole
you know our business thrives on that
platform and we'll continue to do so for
a long time and I'll have links to
self-d disrupt and Zach to your profile
in the show notes so wherever you're
listening to this uh just look in the in
the description the show notes below
you'll be able to find all those links I
think this is the best uh first episode
to have deal makers as the title cuz
Zach you have really run the gamut on
making deals and really making them you
know creating them somewhat out of thin
air I probably would have put more
thought into the Rebrand in the first
episode after the Rebrand if we didn't
have the ultimate deal maker I'm just
GNA keep I'm just gonna keep fluffing
him up yeah yeah very impressive very
impressive thank you for taking the time
it was great talking to you I really
appreciate both your time and thank you
so much for having me on the new
branded dealmaker podcast podcast all
right so this has in episode 13 episode
one I don't know I don't know how this
works anymore we're not going back
to uh we covered so much from building
businesses buying businesses doing deals
putting uh don't not Pitch slapping
people uh risk assumptions uh so much so
much great uh so much nuggets here uh to
learn from uh thanks so much Zach and uh
if you got any value from this episode
please uh like subscribe let us know
what you'd like for us to talk about
next drop us a comment and uh we're all
on LinkedIn thanks
are for my kids for kids kids that's
years and years promise my brother soon
as he fin this do it bigbody